## Evaluation Only. Created with Aspose. Words. Copyright 2003-2021 Aspose Pty Ltd.

# Zidan B. Younis

Mobile (+962) 79 6736326 DOB – POB 20 July 1981 – Kuwait

Email zidanyounis@gmail.com Nationality Jordanian Languages Arabic, English Marital Status Married

## **Summary**

Working in software industry for around 20 years, with 4+ Business Analyzing experience and 7 years Project and program management experience in managing multi-disciplinary teams of varying sizes, and over 15 years in Microsoft development technologies. Has the ability to build strong relationships with all stakeholders and to turn proposals into reality. Has a successful experience in management roles that demands a high level of drive, dedication and a focus on delivering business outcomes through the use of methodologies.

Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP) and a Project Management Professional (PMP) with attendance certificate.

## Skills

#### **Technical**

- ASP.Net C#
- SQL Server
- Front-End development
- Team Foundation Server (TFS)

#### Enterprise solutions

- LMS (Learning Management System)
- DMS (Documents Management System)
- Inventory System
- HMIS (Hospital Management Information System)
- CMS (Content Management System)
- Workflow Management System
- CRM (Customer Relationship Management)

## Management

- Project management PMP and Agile methodologies
- Business requirements analysis
- Creating presentations and demos
- Writing Proposals, technical write-ups, user guide and presentations
- Gantt-chat plans

### **Soft Skills**

- Very good communication skills
- Training and presentation skills

## **Experience**

Perfect Presentation – Ministry of Justice

(Riyadh - Saudi Arabia)

Senior Business Analyst (12/2019 - Present)

Working in a big Agile-Scrum environment in Ministry of Justice - Executive courts system.

This system is serving millions of users through online portals and judges systems. My responsibility is to:

- Working with business stake-holders (Business owner, Delivery manager, Scrum Master, Technical team and QA team)
- Get the requirements from business owner, documents or third-parties meeting
- Create analyzing presentation to get Business owners approval
- Writing BRD
- Writing user-stories on TFS
- Set meetings with any external parties if we need to integrate with
- Support development team in understanding requirements

Created with an evaluation copy of Aspose. Words. To discover the full versions of our APIs please visit: https://products.aspose.com/words/

- Demonstrate requirements to the business owner
- Train new staff
- Analyze integration services requirements

### eSense Software

(Amman – Jordan)

### Implementation Engineer / Business analyst (10/2016 – 10/2019)

I was reporting directly to COO, and I have several responsibilities as below: My Responsibilities:

- Working with business stake-holders (Client, Project manager, Technical team and QA team)
- Traveling to client's country and city
- · Requirements gathering
- Writing BRD
- Handle UAT with the client's team
- Train client users
- Train company's new employees
- Make system user guide
- Support the QA team with understanding Business, correct behaviors, bugs priorities
- Presales tasks (such as live demonstration for potential customers)
- Project coordinator (Manage PMs relation with clients)
- Consultant for the product (Business-whys and technically)
- Support PMs in Project monitoring and control
- Coordinating between client and company team
- Deploy system releases/Fixes/Updates into the client's environment
- Acting as a Team Leader position when needed
- Acting as a Project Manager position when needed
- Help PMs in project planning

Projects management

Paragon Sustainable Business Development (Amman – Jordan)  Media Manager (4/2016 – 10/2016)	Themar Academy (UAE – Abu Dhabi) Senior Web Development (10/2014 – 12/2015)
Manage Software department and do the following tasks:  - Business Analyst - Project Management - Business Development	Developing Themar Owl LMS (Learning Management System)  My Responsibilities:  - System analysis  - Database design  - System development and design  - Train the team  - Support users and clients  - Present the system and make a demos  - Write required documents (Technical write-up, user guides etc.)  - Test the system in each updates
SISCOM – Sawabeh Information Systems Company (Amman – Jordan / Riyadh – KSA) Business Solutions Manager (12/2013 – 7/2014)	Imprint Tech (Amman - Jordan) Executive Manager (3/2012 – 11/2013)
Sawabeh Information Services Company (SISCOM) is a regional technology services firm that define designs and delivers IT-enabled business solutions to its clients. My roles were: - Business development	Imprint tech is a Jordanian company established in 2012 works in software development and IT training.  - Business development - Presales - Projects management

Created with an evaluation copy of Aspose. Words. To discover the full versions of our APIs please visit: https://products.aspose.com/words/

Business analysis

<ul><li>Business analysis</li><li>Team management</li><li>Manage Quality team</li></ul>	<ul><li>Technical Team management</li><li>Manage Quality team</li></ul>
<b>Contractor</b> (4/2010 – 3-2012)	ART (Arab Radio & Television) (Amman – Jordan Branch) <b>Head of Web Development Department</b> (5/2007 – 4/2010)
Work in contract basis with following Jordanian companies:  - Arabic Innovation / Project Manager - First Finance / Senior Developer - Excellent Soft / Project Manager	Developed the ART Online Portal (www.artonline.tv) that won two prizes in the PAN Arab Web Awards, my roles were: - Senior developer - Project management - Requirements analysis
CCS (Computer and Communications Systems Ltd) (Amman – Jordan) .NET Developer/Trainer (5/2006 – 5/2007)	University of Jordan (Amman – Jordan) <b>Programmer</b> (9/2004 - 5/2006)
CCS one of the biggest ITC companies in Jordan. My roles were:Net Developer - Microsoft trainer	<ul> <li>Developed and tested the following applications:</li> <li>Labs management system</li> <li>Ticketing system</li> <li>Attendance system for labs supervisors</li> </ul>

# **Education**

Corllins University (Online Studying)
Bachelors, Computer Science

Al-Jitawi Training Center (Amman - Jordan)

PMP (Project Manager Professional) - Attendance Certificate

Microsoft (Online)
MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) in Visual Basic .NET

**Arab Collage (Amman - Jordan)**Diploma, Information Technology

2010

2009

2005

2001